<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Nico Stern</title><link>https://nicostern.de/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Nico Stern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 04:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicostern.de/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CS50 Quiz</title><link>https://nicostern.de/p/cs50quiz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nicostern.de/p/cs50quiz/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://nicostern.de/p/cs50quiz/cover-cs50quiz.jpg" alt="Featured image of post CS50 Quiz" />&lt;p>View it on &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/nico-fst/cs50quiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Github&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After passing my A-levels, I missed working on projects and having coding targets. Therefore, I prepared for my Bachelor in Computer Science at &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.uni-bonn.de/de" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>University of Bonn&lt;/a> by completing the HarvardX Course &amp;ldquo;CS50&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to Computer Science&amp;rdquo; - look at my cool &lt;a class="link" href="https://certificates.cs50.io/b5e8b380-b3c8-4426-88a7-f10bac14d69d.pdf?size=letter" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>certificate&lt;/a>. CS50 Quiz appears to be my self-chosen final project which I describe like so:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using the knowledge gained througout the ten weeks of CS50x, this Swift code for iOS devices (tested on iPhone 14 Pro running iOS 16) builds a Single Choice QuizApp. The questions are fetched and parsed as .json from a Firestore Database. The project is connected to a Firebase via SDK packages (particulary FireAuth). Since Swift is not covered in the CS50x input, I made use of several online tutorials, eg. for Firebase or .json parsing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CheckMathe</title><link>https://nicostern.de/p/checkmathe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nicostern.de/p/checkmathe/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://nicostern.de/p/checkmathe/cover-creamy.jpg" alt="Featured image of post CheckMathe" />&lt;p>Visit website on [http://checkmathe.de].
TODO: Download in the App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While still in the process of building the app, checkmathe.de is my vision of students and teachers coming together and start learning with the overhead of getting started converging to 0.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the website, new students will be able to search for teachers by &lt;em>CheckMather&lt;/em>, an approach where students filter potential teachers by their expertise.
Students will also be able to book recurring tutorings or &lt;em>InstantCheck&lt;/em>s where we promise to provide a teacher within less than 7 days for emergencies - again filtered by the perfect teacher&amp;rsquo;s knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the iOS (and maybe Android sometimes&amp;hellip;) App, students will be able to view their last tutorings and to have quick access to tutoring materials like PDFs from their teachers. They will be able to book tutorings from anywhere and view pending payments. My dream would be an Apple Pay integration where students can pay on the fly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay stundet for updates :).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Vault</title><link>https://nicostern.de/p/star-vault/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 04:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nicostern.de/p/star-vault/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://nicostern.de/p/star-vault/cover-rainbow.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Star Vault" />&lt;p>On &lt;a class="link" href="https://obsidian.nicostern.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>obsidian.nicostern.de&lt;/a> I plan to develop a subset of my private Obsidian Vault using a Quartz server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I am impressed by it&amp;rsquo;s .md approach combined with the &lt;em>infinite&lt;/em> possibilities provided by the comunity through plugings, Obsidian became my smart journal, habit tracker, project manager and overall second brain - &amp;lsquo;cause remember:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Your mind is for having ideas, not holding them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> &lt;br>
David Allen, &lt;em>Getting Things Done&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The main content I plan to incorporate includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>some of the modules at &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.uni-bonn.de/de" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>University of Bonn&lt;/a> that I have been tutoring, like:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Technical Computer Science (de: &amp;ldquo;Technische Informatik&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Internship In Object-oriented Software Development (de: &amp;ldquo;Praktikum objektorientierte Softwareentwicklung&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scientific based learning techniques&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>